<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | ARAM</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/ci-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/ci-cd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;continuous-integration-and-continuous-deployment-cicd&#34;&gt;Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern software development, Continuous Integration (CI) and Continuous Deployment/Delivery (CD) are critical practices, particularly within DevOps.
These methodologies automate various stages of development, enabling faster and more reliable product releases by reducing the risk of errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;continuous-integration-ci&#34;&gt;Continuous Integration (CI)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Integration is a practice where developers frequently merge their code changes into a shared repository, often several times a day.
The key objective of CI is to catch and resolve bugs early, especially those that arise when multiple developers&amp;rsquo; changes interact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CI relies on automated tests, which run after each commit to ensure that new changes don’t break the codebase. If the tests pass, the changes are merged into the main branch, helping to maintain a stable and functional project state.
Popular CI tools include Jenkins, GitLab CI, and Travis CI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;continuous-deployment-cd&#34;&gt;Continuous Deployment (CD)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuous Deployment and Continuous Delivery build on CI but with different levels of automation in the release process:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Delivery&lt;/strong&gt; ensures that after CI, the code is automatically prepared for release into production,
but a manual review or approval step is still required before deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; fully automates this process, automatically pushing code into production after all
testing phases are successfully completed, allowing for quicker releases without human intervention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;benefits-of-cicd&#34;&gt;Benefits of CI/CD&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Early bug detection and conflict resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Faster delivery of new features and fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced time to market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved software stability and quality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By integrating CI/CD into their workflows, teams can adapt more swiftly to changing requirements and release updates with minimal risk,
making these practices a standard in today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced development environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
